Collection of Bob Bartlett, 1935-1948
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Collection of Bob Bartlett, 1935-1948
MS 116
Bartlett, Bob
The collections is comprised of correspondence written 1935 – 1945 between Bartlett and his friend Morris. Also contained within the collection are two typescripts by Morris; illustrated magazine articles authored by Bartlett; black and white photographs depicting Bartlett, Artic inhabitants, wildlife, icebergs, the ship and its crew members; as well as a 16mm black and white film which documents Bartlett’s voyages.
0.2 Linear Feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
Bartlett was an Arctic explorer from Newfoundland; Morris was a store manager for Standard Brands, New York City.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 5 series
Series I: Correspondence, 1935-1945
Series II: Clippings and Maps, 1935-1948
Series III: Articles, 1935-1946
Series IV: Ralph B. Morris' Manuscripts, Undated
Series V: Visual materials, 1935-1938, undated
Scope and Content Note
Predominantly written descriptions and visual images of Bartlett's travels. Correspondence is between Bartlett and his friend Morris, 1935 to 1945. Two typescripts by Morris: "To Newfoundland by Sail" and "Deep Water" describe trips he took aboard Bartlett's schooner, the "Effie M. Morrissey." Among the illustrated magazine articles are some written by Bartlett for National Geographic Magazine and Smithsonian Explorations. Newspaper clippings about "Captain Bob Bartlett," as he was known, are from the New York Times, and include his obituary. Black-and-white photographs depict Bartlett, Arctic inhabitants, wildlife, icebergs, the ship and its crew members. Maps, color slides, and a 16 mm black-and-white film document Bartlett's numerous voyages.
Access Terms
Morris, Ralph Bartlett
Effie M. Morrissey (Schooner)
Adventure and adventurers -- Arctic regions
Icebergs -- Photographs
Eskimos -- Photographs
Schooners -- Slides
Arctic regions -- Discovery and exploration
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence, 1935-1945
  - Letters, 1935-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Clippings and Maps, 1935-1948
  - Letters, 1935-1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series III: Articles, 1935-1946
  - Offprints of Articles, 1935 - 1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series IV: Ralph B. Morris' Manuscripts, Undated
  - Ralph B. Morris Manuscripts: "Deep Water" and "To Newfoundland by Sail", Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series V: Visual materials, 1935-1938, undated
  - Photographs: Robert A. Bartlett, 1935, 1936, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photographs: The "Effie Morrissey" Staff and Crew, 1937, 1938, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs: Icebergs, 1938, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photographs: Land, Eskimos, Wildlife, 1935, 1937, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 16mm Black and White Film, undated (Box 2)